Guide to the Anonymous nudist and erotic photography collection, 1930s-1970s.
Anonymous nudist and erotic photography collection
Division of Rare and Manuscript Collections, Cornell University Library
Anonymous nudist and erotic photography collection, 1930s-1970s.
7781
4 cubic feet.
Correspondence, movie film, photographs, publications, slides
Division of Rare and Manuscript Collections, Cornell University Library
Photographic prints, slides, negatives, and short films; publications, brochures, books, and correspondence surrounding the work and personal life of a studio photographer who was active in New York City in the 1960s and 1970s.
The New York Institute of Photography was founded in 1910 to train people in professional photography.
COLLECTION DESCRIPTION
Photographic prints, slides, negatives, and short films; publications, brochures, books, and correspondence surrounding the work and personal life of a studio photographer who was active in New York City in the 1960s and 1970s. Visual materials in the collection include 960 photographic prints, 2212 slides, 490 negatives, and 11 motion pictures. Categories of material include professional work; personal images and ephemera; personal nudes; and erotica. Most of the images in the professional category are studio portraits and photographs of artists and their work, or of the artwork itself, many from "Club Burr," evidently a group of artists in New York City; another subgroup in the professional category relates to the collector's studies at the New York Institute of Photography.
Personal images include 600 slides, negatives and prints of female nudes, most of them studio shots reminiscent of photographs in Playboy magazine in the 1960s and 1970s; and images taken at an unidentified nudist colony, circa 1960s. The erotic visual materials include photos of male and female nudes, and nude self-portraits resembling "physique" photos by noted photographers such as Bruce of L.A., Douglas of Detroit, Your Model Service and AMG/Bob Mizer, as well as erotic films.
SUBJECTS
Names:
Bruce, of Los Angeles.; Douglas, of Detroit.; Mizer, Bob.; Athletic Model Guild.; Club Burr (Group of artists); New York Institute of Photography.; Your Model Service.
Subjects:
Photography of women.; Photography of men.; Nudists.; Photography, Erotic.; Photographers -- New York (State) -- New York.
Form and Genre Terms:
Photographs.
INFORMATION FOR USERS
SERIES LIST
Series I. Professional photography by the Photographer
Boxes 1, 2, 6
Business Files
Fine Arts Photography
Other
Series II. Nudism
Boxes 3, 4, 6
Professional Photography
Amateur Photography
Casual Photography
ASA/ESA
Series III. Erotica
Boxes 3, 6
Erotica Collection
Photographer's Erotica
Erotica Businesses
Series IV. Personal
Boxes 3, 6
Personal Papers
Photographs
Series V. New York Institute of Photography grades and tests
Boxes 3-5
Documents
Artwork
Series VI. Negatives
Box 3
Series VII. 8mm Films
Box 7
CONTAINER LIST
- Series I. Professional photography by the Photographer
  - Business Files
    - Photography invoices, 1994-1998 (Box 1, Folder 1)
    - Resume (Box 1, Folder 2)
    - Invitations to artshows, galleries, exhibits (Box 1, Folder 3)
    - Model Release (Box 1, Folder 65)
    - Portfolio (Box 1, Folder 66)
    - Professional work correspondence (Box 1, Folder 67)
  - Fine Arts Photography
    - Job notes, instruction, preparation, 1994 (Box 1, Folder 4)
    - Amundsen painting (Box 1, Folder 5)
    - Fine arts photography slides (Box 1, Folder 6)
    - Frances Heatherington (Box 1, Folder 7)
    - Paintings (Box 1, Folder 8)
    - Sculptures (Box 1, Folder 9)
    - Sculptures (Box 1, Folder 10)
    - Sculptures (Box 1, Folder 11)
    - Sculptures (Box 1, Folder 12)
    - Sculptures (Box 1, Folder 13)
    - CLWAC at NAC, November 7, 1972 (Box 1, Folder 14)
    - Duncan, Tom (Box 1, Folder 15)
    - Manship, John (Box 1, Folder 16)
    - Stefanelli, Joe (Box 1, Folder 17)
    - Weber, Marilyn (Box 1, Folder 18)
    - Van Hook, Nell (Box 1, Folder 19)
    - Weichberger, Philip (Box 1, Folder 20)
    - Wolins, Joe (Box 1, Folder 21)
    - Shulman, Morris, 1983 (Box 1, Folder 22)
    - Shore, Lillian (Box 1, Folder 23)
    - Shibley, Gertrude (Box 1, Folder 24)
    - Secunda, Art, 12 November-3 December 1971 (Box 1, Folder 25)
    - Park, Mike (Box 1, Folder 26)
    - Ponce de Leone, Michael (Box 1, Folder 27)
    - Moore, Bruce (Box 1, Folder 28)
    - Manship, Margaret Cassidy (Box 1, Folder 29)
    - Manco, Albino (Box 1, Folder 30)
    - McKesson, Malcolm, November 20, 1972 (Box 1, Folder 31)
    - McBride, Lucia (Box 1, Folder 32)
    - Lee, Eleanor Gay (Box 1, Folder 33)
    - Lasch, Pat (Box 1, Folder 34)
    - Josephs, Cliff (Box 1, Folder 35)
    - Golden, Eunice, March 27, 1979 (Box 1, Folder 36)
    - Gluckman, Morris (Box 1, Folder 37)
    - Gentle, Esther, November 7, 1977 (Box 1, Folder 38)
    - Fox, Marilyn (Box 1, Folder 39)
    - Fletcher, Helen (Box 1, Folder 40)
    - Farley, Marsha (Box 1, Folder 41)
    - De Miskey, Julian (Box 1, Folder 42)
    - De Miskey, Shari Frisch (Box 1, Folder 43)
    - Dawson, Eve (Box 1, Folder 44)
    - Boal, Sara (Box 1, Folder 45)
    - Betzak, Ida (Box 1, Folder 46)
    - Belag, Harriet, February 22, 1977-September 9, 1983 (Box 1, Folder 47)
    - Albertazzi, Mario (Box 1, Folder 48)
    - Arye, Leonora (Box 1, Folder 49)
    - Fine arts slides (Box 1, Folder 68)
    - Paintings and sculptures negatives (Box 6)
    - Amundsen painting negatives (Box 6)
    - Painting negatives (Box 6)
    - Painting negatives (Box 6)
    - Painting negatives (Box 6)
  - Other
    - Ed Walsh (Box 1, Folder 50)
    - Nerfetiti/Devonia Evangeline, October 31, 1980 (Box 1, Folder 51)
    - Subway (Box 1, Folder 52)
    - Photographs of various people, places, objects (Box 1, Folder 53)
    - Fire at 30 St and 12 Ave, NYC, January 1977 (Box 1, Folder 54)
    - Men-Black and White (Box 1, Folder 55)
    - New York City-Rockefeller Center (Box 1, Folder 56)
    - Religion: Interior R.C. Church (Box 1, Folder 57)
    - Sanitation (Box 1, Folder 58)
    - Sanitation-Snow Removal (Box 1, Folder 59)
    - Transportation-Highway, Black and White (Box 1, Folder 60)
    - Teilman, Gunvor Bull (Box 1, Folder 61)
    - Overstreet, Joe, March 20, 1981, February 3, 1989 (Box 1, Folder 62)
    - Gonzalez, Maritza, January 26, 1981 (Box 1, Folder 63)
    - Zaleski, Jean (Box 1, Folder 64)
    - Historical-Color (Box 2, Folder 1)
    - Alcoholism-Color (Box 2, Folder 2)
    - Advertising-Color (Box 2, Folder 3)
    - Animals-Color (Box 2, Folder 4)
    - Appliance-Color (Box 2, Folder 5)
    - Architecture-Color (Box 2, Folder 6)
    - Automobile-Color (Box 2, Folder 7)
    - Bridges-Color (Box 2, Folder 8)
    - Business-Offices (Box 2, Folder 9)
    - Circus-Color (Box 2, Folder 10)
    - Children-Color (Box 2, Folder 11)
    - Consumerism-color (Box 2, Folder 12)
    - Consumerism: Super Market-color (Box 2, Folder 13)
    - Crowds-color (Box 2, Folder 14)
    - Demolition-color (Box 2, Folder 15)
    - Families-color (Box 2, Folder 16)
    - Farms-color (Box 2, Folder 17)
    - Faucet-color (Box 2, Folder 18)
    - Fire-color (Box 2, Folder 19)
    - Food-color (Box 2, Folder 20)
    - Hands-color (Box 2, Folder 21)
    - Holidays: Halloween-color (Box 2, Folder 22)
    - Construction-color (Box 2, Folder 23)
    - Holidays: Memorial Day-color (Box 2, Folder 24)
    - Hospitals-color (Box 2, Folder 25)
    - Housing: Rural color (Box 2, Folder 26)
    - Housing: Suburban-color (Box 2, Folder 27)
    - Mannequins-color (Box 2, Folder 28)
    - Men-color (Box 2, Folder 29)
    - Miscellaneous: Family and Friends-color (Box 2, Folder 30)
    - Money-color (Box 2, Folder 31)
    - nature-color (Box 2, Folder 32)
    - New York: City Hall-color (Box 2, Folder 33)
    - New York: Financial District-color (Box 2, Folder 34)
    - New York: Street Scenes-color (Box 2, Folder 35)
    - Occupations-color (Box 2, Folder 36)
    - Parades-color (Box 2, Folder 37)
    - Police-color (Box 2, Folder 38)
    - Pornography-color (Box 2, Folder 39)
    - Printing Industry-color (Box 2, Folder 40)
    - Puzzle (Box 2, Folder 41)
    - Religion-color (Box 2, Folder 42)
    - Restaurants-color (Box 2, Folder 43)
    - Rust-color (Box 2, Folder 44)
    - Sanitation-color (Box 2, Folder 45)
    - Senior Citizens-color (Box 2, Folder 46)
    - Signs-color (Box 2, Folder 47)
    - Sports-color (Box 2, Folder 48)
    - Suburbs-color (Box 2, Folder 49)
    - Swings (Box 2, Folder 50)
    - Teenagers-color (Box 2, Folder 51)
    - Transportation-color (Box 2, Folder 52)
    - Weather-color (Box 2, Folder 53)
    - Women-color (Box 2, Folder 54)
    - Zoo-color (Box 2, Folder 55)
    - Appliances (Box 2, Folder 56)
    - Photographer's Family-black and white (Box 2, Folder 57)
    - Children-black and white (Box 2, Folder 58)
    - Education-black and white (Box 2, Folder 59)
    - Electricity-black and white (Box 2, Folder 60)
    - Families-black and white (Box 2, Folder 61)
    - Food-black and white (Box 2, Folder 62)
    - Food: Candy (Box 2, Folder 63)
    - Hands (Box 2, Folder 64)
    - Housing: Suburban-black and white (Box 2, Folder 65)
    - CA Contacts and Negatives (Box 2, Folder 66)
    - Random assortment of photographs (Box 2, Folder 67)
    - Prometheus (Box 6)
    - Prometheus 2 (Box 6)
    - City Hall (Box 6)
    - Marge's church, sculpture (Box 6)
    - Henri Janson (Box 6)
    - Lincoln Center and Church Demolition (Box 6)
    - Lincoln Center slides (Box 6)
- Series II. Nudism
  - Professional Photography
    - Female nude (Box 3, Folder 1)
    - Female nude in the woods (Box 3, Folder 2)
    - Photographer (Box 3, Folder 3)
    - Female nude in a meadow (Box 4, Folder 1)
    - Female nude (Box 6)
  - Amateur Photography
    - Photographer and female nude in the woods and meadows (Box 3, Folder 4)
    - Female nude (Box 3, Folder 5)
    - Female nude in a bedroom (Box 3, Folder 6)
    - Female nude in a bedroom (Box 3, Folder 7)
    - Mother and newborn (Box 3, Folder 8)
    - Photographer and friends (Box 3, Folder 9)
  - Casual Photography
    - Photographer at home (Box 3, Folder 10)
    - Photographer (Box 3, Folder 11)
    - Photographer and female partner in the woods (Box 3, Folder 12)
    - Photographer camping (Box 3, Folder 13)
    - Photographer camping (Box 3, Folder 14)
    - Photographer and friends, cabin (Box 3, Folder 15)
  - ASA/ESA
    - The ASA Bulletin, April-May 1974 (Box 3, Folder 16)
    - American Sunbathing Association (ASA) (Box 3, Folder 17)
    - ESA/ASA gathering, 1958-1964 (Box 3, Folder 18)
    - ESA and ASA gathering (Box 3, Folder 19)
    - Red containers-ASA gathering, 1964 (Box 6)
- Series III. Erotica
  - Erotica Collection
    - Photograph collection (Box 3, Folder 20)
    - Photograph collection (Box 3, Folder 21)
    - Photograph collection (Box 3, Folder 22)
      masked heterosexual pair
    - Photograph collection (Box 3, Folder 23)
    - Photograph collection (Box 3, Folder 24)
    - Photograph collection (Box 3, Folder 25)
      Two females
    - Erotic dancer (Box 3, Folder 26)
    - Photographs of exhibit of erotica artwork (Box 3, Folder 27)
    - Deck of cards (Box 6)
    - Box of matches (Box 6)
  - Photographer's Erotica
    - Photographer's amateur erotica (Box 3, Folder 28)
    - Photographer's professional erotica (Box 3, Folder 29)
      Photographer and female partner (Freda)
  - Erotica Businesses
    - "Swingers Media" (Box 3, Folder 30)
    - "Scenes: The Orgy-A Compendium", November 1969 (Box 3, Folder 31)
    - Photo Illustrated (Box 3, Folder 32)
    - Erik Imports-film, magazine, novel, sex toy distributor (Box 3, Folder 33)
    - Marlowe Sales-magazine and film distributor (Box 3, Folder 34)
    - Diverse Industries, Inc.-Adult erotica catalog, 1976 (Box 3, Folder 35)
    - Foto-care Ltd.-film distributor (Box 3, Folder 36)
    - Eve's Dream-swingers service (Box 3, Folder 37)
    - Interracial Swingers-dating service (Box 3, Folder 38)
    - Blue Bird Boutique, Inc.-film distributor, 1977 (Box 3, Folder 39)
    - Ultima-film distributor (Box 3, Folder 40)
    - Male prostitute business card with rates (Box 3, Folder 41)
    - Sensual greeting card (Box 3, Folder 42)
- Series IV. Personal
  - Personal Papers
    - Letters from Beatrice Foster, 1952 (Box 3, Folder 43)
    - Letters from Beatrice Foster, 1952 (Box 3, Folder 44)
    - Correspondence between Photographer, parents, and sister, 1953-1954 (Box 3, Folder 45)
    - Correspondence between Photographer and acquaintances, 1942-1985 (Box 3, Folder 46)
    - Letter to Freda Leinwand, October 19, 2008 (Box 3, Folder 47)
    - Pages from books and newspapers with living tips (Box 3, Folder 48)
    - Bill Shustick Prints, 1978 (Box 3, Folder 49)
    - Rio de Janeiro brochure (Box 3, Folder 50)
    - Correspondence with attorneys to sell land in Alaska, 1953 (Box 3, Folder 51)
    - Documentation of Photographer's work as a seaman on various steamers, 1951-1953 (Box 3, Folder 52)
    - Legal dispute with US Selective Service System, 1952-1985 (Box 3, Folder 53)
    - Binder: The Signal School training manual, January 1, 1952 (Box 3, Folder 54)
    - Photographer's life documents-legal papers, rental agreements, etc., May 15, 1928-August 6, 2008 (Box 3, Folder 55)
    - Documents labeled "Photographer's Important Papers", 1955-2008 (Box 3, Folder 56)
    - Pins and patches (Box 3, Folder 57)
      Camp Archery Assn.; North American Hunting Club; Signal SVC BN
    - Address book (Box 3, Folder 58)
    - Collection of photographs of Photographer throughout his life (Box 3, Folder 59)
    - Photographer's Death, August 6, 2008 (Box 3, Folder 60)
    - Matchbox with an image of a woman in a bathing suit on the cover, whose suit comes off when you open the box. (Box 6)
  - Photographs
    - Arizona (Box 3, Folder 61)
    - Friends (Box 3, Folder 62)
    - Diving contest, August 14, 1946 (Box 3, Folder 63)
    - Candid photos with friends at the beachm, fair, pool (Box 3, Folder 64)
    - Sailing (Box 3, Folder 65)
    - Hunting, camping (Box 3, Folder 66)
    - Photographer and friends-random assortment of photos (Box 3, Folder 67)
    - Photographer self-portraits (Box 3, Folder 68)
    - Photographs from Beatrice Foster (Box 3, Folder 69)
    - Various photos of Photographer (Box 6)
- Series V. New York Institute of Photography grades and tests
  - Documents
    - Photo development instructions (Box 3, Folder 70)
    - Color transparencies (Box 3, Folder 71)
    - Portraiture Notes (Box 3, Folder 72)
    - NYIP grades and tests, 1958-1960 (Box 3, Folder 73)
    - Portrait negativies (Box 3, Folder 74)
  - Artwork
    - Technique practice (Box 4, Folder 2)
    - Colorized black an white photography practice (Box 4, Folder 3)
    - Portraits (Box 4, Folder 4)
    - Object Photography (Box 4, Folder 5)
    - Portraits (Box 4, Folder 6)
    - General Photography (Box 4, Folder 7)
    - General Photography (Box 4, Folder 8)
    - Portraits (Box 4, Folder 9)
    - Portraits (Box 4, Folder 10)
    - Portraits (Box 4, Folder 11)
    - Portraits (Box 5, Folder 1)
    - Colorized black and white photos (Box 5, Folder 2)
    - Portraits (Box 5, Folder 3)
    - Portraits (Box 5)
- Series VI. Negatives
  - Fine Arts (Box 3, Folder 75)
  - Professional Photographs (Box 3, Folder 76)
  - Nudes (Box 3, Folder 77)
  - Erotica (Box 3, Folder 78)
  - Personal photographs (Box 3, Folder 79)
- Series VII. 8mm Films
  Some are amateur footage, some are commercial pornography.
  - "3's A Crowd" and "A Man's Everything", 802 (Box 7)
  - "Vas", "Blonde", and "Mixer, 803 (Box 7)
  - "Sandwich" and "Crib Time", 804 (Box 7)
  - "Doing Their Thing", 805 (Box 7)
  - "One Man", 806 (Box 7)
  - Unknown erotica, 807 (Box 7)
  - Frisco-girls, 808 (Box 7)
  - Unknown erotica, 809 (Box 7)
  - Boys Are Next, 810 (Box 7)
  - Unknown erotica, 811 (Box 7)
  - Unknown erotica, 812 (Box 7)
  - Personal film, 813 (Box 7)
  - Personal film, 814 (Box 7)
  - Personal film, 815 (Box 7)
  - Personal film - Dog and Me, 816 (Box 7)
  - Personal film - nudes, 817 (Box 7)
  - Personal film - nudes, 818 (Box 7)
  - Personal film - friends, 819 (Box 7)
  - Personal film - nudes, 820 (Box 7)